three things I like about the rep
Fitness Double Black Diamond Bar are the
sharp Mountain knurling the fact it
comes in three different finishes and it
has a tensile strength rating of 200 000
PSI I know I talk a whole lot about
multi-purpose bars and how they can be a
really solid addition to a home gym but
if you're somebody who only wants to
focus on powerlifting well then going
after a dedicated power lifting bar is
definitely the way to go this is one of
my favorite options on the market right
now there's a whole lot to break down so
let's get right to it
what's up it's Jake back in the barbing
garage gym and today we're gonna be
breaking down the rep Fitness Double
Black Diamond power bar this is rep's
new flagship power lifting bar it's
meant to go head-to-head with the best
power lifting bars out there and we're
going to talk about a lot today
specifically we're going to talk about
some pros and cons we're going to talk
about some money and we're also going to
talk about who should or maybe should
not purchase this barbell one quick
thing though before I start doing all
that we've reviewed a whole lot of
barbells and barbin.com I think you
should go and check out our best list we
made all you got to do is search bar Ben
best barbells it's going to pull right
up for you you're gonna find out for
yourself which ones we like the best who
knows you might even be surprised which
one cracks that number one spot
foreign
okay so for anybody who doesn't know
what a power lifting bar is it's a
barbell that's dedicated specifically to
the big three of power lifting which is
squat bench and dead lift all right so
these barbells are going to have one
normal markings ipf standard
international powerlifting Federation
it's basically for you to have identical
hand placement you know like when you're
going to do a wide grip bench press for
example you're going to have minimal to
pretty much no spin in the loading
sleeves so you know performing Olympic
style lifts really isn't you know you're
not going to be very successful with a
barbell like this plus the knurling is
going to be sharper you know compared to
multi-purpose and Olympic bars and
you're going to find all those traits
with the Double Black Diamond Bar so it
does in fact have a 29 millimeter
diameter I really like that you know it
really fills up your hands when you're
going to lift and it's going to just
give you you know a solid grip speaking
of grip I really like the knurling right
here on this bar it's a mountain style
knurling so each individual marking
sticks up like a mountain wood now not
everybody's you know crazy about
Mountain knurling because it you know
it's more aggressive than a volcano
neural but you know I really like what
rep has done right here you know it's
not too abrasive now it's definitely
still sharp but it feels good you know
there's other barbells like bells of
Steel bare naked power lifting bar which
I really like that bar but it's a whole
lot sharper than this one right here so
I think you know rep did a really good
job and that's because you know all
these markings are really you know
packed in here together as opposed to
being kind of spaced out and sitting a
little bit taller you only have one
neural marking right here as I mentioned
it's for you know ipf ipf standard right
here you do have bronze bushings in the
loading sleeves so you're going to get
you know a little bit of a spin but you
know
you definitely don't want to do any type
of you know power cleans or hang cleans
or anything like that because it's not
going to spin as well as an Olympic Bar
wheel but also you know this knurling is
pretty sharp so you definitely don't
want to be doing that you can load up to
1500 pounds on this bar which is plenty
of weight for you know 99 of athletes
and it has a tensile strength rating of
200 000 PSI that's a really solid number
it's going to tell you tensile strength
is going to tell you how strong a bar is
now some bars like force USA their
Gunner bar is rated 235 000 PSI that's
really strong I don't think everybody
necessarily needs that it's nice but 200
000 is definitely going to be able to
get the job done and you know when it
comes to those cons money could be an
issue for some people I think it's this
is a competitively priced barbell I'm
going to talk about detail all the money
in just a little bit but cheapest
version is still 330 bucks you can find
a cheaper one out there like I said that
Bell's a steel bare naked bar that's
220. so it kind of just depends on your
budget but you know at the same time
you're definitely getting your money's
worth right here and then you know I
already mentioned you know you don't
want to do any type of dynamic movements
you know explosive power cleans or
anything like that and that's because
this is you know a dedicated power
lifting bar so it's just not very
versatile
foreign
[Music]
you know the price tag you're going to
be paying for this barbell it's going to
depend on the finish that you decide to
go with all right so the staircode
option we have right here 330 bucks they
have a stainless steel with hard Chrome
loading sleeves that's going to run you
around 400 bucks and the fully stainless
steel option that's gonna be around 450
450 bucks that's a lot it's actually
more than the Rogue Ohio power bar of
the stainless steel version it's around
415 but with Rogue you got to pay for
shipping and rep you don't so maybe you
know it kind of balances out a little
bit now
there's 330 bucks this is a pretty sweet
price point in my opinion but you can
definitely go down a cheaper route I
already mentioned the bells of Steel
bare naked power lifting bar it's going
to run around 220 bucks you know it's
only 110 whatever it might not make that
big of a deal for some people but you
know that does free up a little bit of
wiggle room for a weight bench maybe you
know some adjustable dumbbells or you
know whatever the case is it frees up
over a hundred dollars so it could could
be a big deal for some right now 450
bucks I just mentioned that's a chunk of
change but you're also you know getting
the highest level of protection from
rust and corrosion possible so that
might be you know worth that extra money
for somebody plus stainless steel you
tend to get a better grip than a bar
that has an actual coating on it I
personally you know don't feel
compromised with this one right here
with the cerakote but that's something
to think about as well
[Music]
okay so I've already talked about you
know the max weight capacity intensible
strength rating but let's get a little
bit more into the nitty-gritty with the
specs here so once again this is a
cerakote barbell but the loading sleeves
are actually DuraCoat so DuraCoat is a
chemical process that rep is doing with
the loading sleeves basically it's
hardening that outer shell I guess you
could call it of the steel making it
more wear resistant and you know more
resistant to rust and corrosion all
right so this bar is 86.6 inches long
it's got 16.3 inch loading sleeves and
the shaft has a diameter of 29
millimeters you only have one normal
marking once again it's ipf standard and
you have bronze bushings in the loading
sleeve so you get a little bit of spin
right there but it's really you know
nothing to write home about the loading
sleeves are in fact smooth as butter you
know so there's not any you know Bridges
group pattern or anything on those
sleeves but some people may not like
that you know because those Groove
ridges you know they're meant to keep
your plates in their original placement
either way you still need weight collars
so it might not be you know that big of
a deal now the knurling is in fact as I
mentioned you know pretty you know
aggressive Mountain style knurling also
you know you do have that Center Knoll
right here and it's the same
abrasiveness as where you put your hands
so definitely keep that in mind you know
it might be a little too sharp on your
upper back that's something you don't
like then I would suggest you know
trying to find a barbell that doesn't
have that now compared to you know last
year's version of their power bar I
think this is definitely an upgrade so I
have the stainless steel one actually
behind me right now and honestly I think
the grip overall you know grip I'm able
to get right here from the knurling is
actually better than that stainless
steel one that's not always the case you
know stainless steel there's no coating
you know so typically when you have a
barbell that has you know a coating like
this right here you know that extra
layer you know in between your hand and
the bark can make it be a little bit
slippery at times but I haven't found
that to be the case with this bar
whatsoever so I think that's a really
nice thing all right so I just want to
you know show you guys some things up
close and basically reiterate on some
other stuff I've talked about too start
with this end cap right here with a
double black as you know it's just
labeled right there 20 kilograms Double
Black Diamond I really like what rep has
done with their end caps right here they
just you know shown a little bit more
attention to detail and everything and I
just I really like that it's just kind
of creative now these are the DuraCoat
sleeves right here something that I
noticed on rep's website is that they
actually you know go ahead and mention
if you notice any type of scratches on
these sleeves what you're probably doing
is pulling Material off the inside of
your loading plates because of how you
know durable and how basically how tough
this sleeve is so if you notice that
just kind of wipe it off and it'll
probably go away you know these as you
can see smooth as glass right there I
don't personally have a problem with it
at all but you know some people might
also really quick I like how it kind of
tapers off a little bit right here so it
makes it easier for you to load and
unload your plates you do have bronze
bushings in the sleeves right there so
you're getting you know a decent amount
of spin but this definitely isn't a bar
that you want to sit here and try to do
a power clean with this knurling is just
going to kind of rip your hands to
shreds and I don't think you want that
if you do go for it but I don't that you
do um these are these are
self-lubricating bronze bushings right
here so you shouldn't have to worry
about taking the sleeve off and
re-lubricating everything but you can if
you want there's a snap ring right there
on the end you can take it off and take
the sleeve off and do all of that now
when it comes to the knurling right here
once again you do have you know the ipf
neural marking right here but overall
knurling it's pretty aggressive and it's
kind of a play on words with the name
Double Black Diamond so I don't know if
you all are familiar with snowboarding
skiing whatever double blacks are the
most difficult terrain you know they're
the steepest and that's kind of what
they're getting at here so it's Mountain
early mountains Double Black Diamond but
it's also you know pretty sharp and it's
basically it's it's more aggressive more
difficult which is kind of like I said
just a play on words now it gives you
really solid grip you know my deadlifts
and everything like I don't feel
compromised at all now one thing that
some people may not be crazy about is
this Center neural right here it's
pretty you know it's the same
abrasiveness and you know if you're
doing you know shoulder press you know
and it's sitting right here here on your
chest and hitting you it might kind of
rub your raw a little bit you might not
like that plus you might not like how
you know it digs into your back whenever
you go to do a back squat I personally
kind of like that just to give me a
little bit extra traction when I go to
do my squats but that's definitely
something that might not you know be
ideal for everybody and I really like
how it is in fact 29 millimeters in
diameter really fills my palm and just
continues to give me a good grip at all
times now when deciding whether or not
this is a good barbell for you to
purchase it it's pretty easy honestly so
somebody who you just want to power lift
this is you know gonna be a really good
option for you to consider plus the 330
price tag I think it's a pretty
affordable price tag so if you're
somebody who you know doesn't want to go
and spend 500 on a barbell or 450 like
you can on the stainless steel one with
this then I think 330 is a really solid
price now yes there's cheaper ones out
there you know I mentioned that bill is
a steel pair naked one
220 bucks yeah but it's also because
it's bare steel so it's not going to
have any rust and corrosion resistance
you have to clean it a lot with the
cerakote you don't have to clean it as
bad not as much upkeep so 330 bucks I
mean that's a really solid price point
that being said 330 is still 330 dollars
and even potentially 450. so if you do
want to go after you know one of those
cheaper ones and you don't care that
it's bare steel you can definitely do so
and then really it's just you know your
style of lifting you know if you don't
care about power lifts that much or
maybe you want to borrow that you can
simply just do it all with well then I
definitely think you should go and check
out some other options you know repin
does in fact have the Colorado bar which
is the same price tag but it's an actual
multi-purpose bar so you can do all of
your lifts with it
all right well that's a wrap on today's
review over the rep Fitness Double Black
Diamond Bar yeah I know that stainless
steel can be pretty pricey but honestly
330 bucks for the cerakote right here is
a really sweet price point in my eyes
it's pretty much my baby right now when
it comes to my power lifts you know the
knurling is really nice you know it's
not too abrasive it's it's that sweet
spot for a power bar and you can load a
ton of weight on it thanks for watching
y'all I hope this video was really
helpful and I was able to break down
everything there is to know about this
barbell as always keep your eyes posted
for my next review but for now head over
to barbin.com because we have a full
written review about this bar just
waiting for you to read all you gotta do
is search bar Bend rep Fitness Double
Black Diamond Bar review it's gonna pull
right up for you you can go over all the
details of everything we discussed here
today I'll catch y'all next time
thank you